# PETER LOWE

## WEB DEVELOPER

💌 peter.lowe42@gmail.com 🚱 http://peterlowe42.github.io/ 📞 5202338947 👂 San Diego, CA 🕠 peterlowe42

#### **SUMMARY**

A professional web developer with a commitment to quality code and user experience. Motivated self paced learner with the ability to quickly pick up new languages and frameworks. Experience working with both front and back end code.

### **EMPLOYMENT**

Nov 2016 to Jul 2017 Reliasoft · Associate Software Engineer · Tucson, Arizona

Full stack development and maintenance on two web applications built in asp.NET, HTML5 and Javacript with options for either SQL or Oracle databases. Within a few weeks of joining the company, I became the sole developer on one of the applications. Despite having no previous experience with .net, I was able to quickly familiarize myself with the framework and make significant contributions to the code base. Shipped thousands of lines of code and built numerous new features from the ground up.

May 2015 to Aug 2015 Sail Caribbean · Video Marketing · British Virgin Islands (BVI)

Shot, edited and produced a series of promotional videos for Sail Caribbean, a sailing summer camp based in the BVI. Coordinated all production activities in close collaboration to ensure the project was successfully completed on-time, under-budget and to the high

standard expected by the client.

Apr 2013 to May 2015 Koh Tao Pro Video · Underwater Videographer · Koh Tao, Thailand

Filmed and edited underwater videos in a range of challenging environments and with tight time constraints whilst ensuring a high

quality final product.

Apr 2012 to Jan 2013 Aqua-center Diving · SCUBA Instructor · Flamingo Beach, Costa Rica

Responsible for the training and safety of a diverse range of clientele. Produced daily dive plans that allowed clients to see the best

that local waters had to offer whilst staying within their level of skill and training.

Oct 2011 to Apr 2012 NeverDry Video · Underwater Videographer · Bocas Del Toro, Panama

I started out at NeverDry as a trainee and continued on as a full-time employee producing underwater videos for divers and

promotional material for local businesses.

Sep 2010 to Oct 2011 Sailing Club Divers · Divernaster/Instructor · Nha Trang, Vietnam

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Dev Bootcamp

Nov 2015 - March 2016

Spent 19 weeks thoroughly immersed in learning Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, JavasScript, Jquery, Ajax and more. I worked closely with various teams to complete challenges, learn new technologies and produce apps. I gained a solid grounding in the skills required for full stack web development. Most importantly, I have mastered the ability to dive head first into new technologies and manage my own learning.

#### The University Of Manchester

Bachelor of Engineering Mechanical Engineering

Sept 2004 - June 2008

The engineering programs at Manchester focus heavily on group projects. This allowed me to develop excellent interpersonal skills and taught me to collaborate effectively with a wide range of people. My studies culminated in a dissertation on the simulation and optimization of tidal stream turbines.

#### **SKILLS**

WEB DEVELOPMENT Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Html5, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Git, React.js, .Net, VB, Wordpress, PHP,

Bootstrap, Foundation

VIDEO EDITING Premiere Pro , After Effects, Audition

3D MODELING AND ANIMATION Blender3D

# **PROJECTS**

Mar 2016 to Apr 2016 Dive Directory

Dive Directory is an open source web app designed to help scuba divers find great places to dive. The user can simply enter a location and dive directory will find dive sites near that location and display them on a map. Users can also post reviews of sites that they have

dived and read reviews that other users have posted.

thedivedirectory.co.uk

2017 to Current Gurl Adventures

A blog app focusing on stories about women doing exciting and adventurous things. The site is still in development but a demo version can be found at the address below. Build in Ruby on Rails the site has a back-end CMS to allow site admins to add and manage content. The front end is built using foundation, jQuery, scss and html. It should be ready for launch in the near future.

There are still a few features I wish to add and we are waiting to build up enough content before launch.

gurladventures.herokuapp.com